乔伊，你在吗？
Joey? Are you in there?
-是瑞秋 -你得跟她谈一谈
-That's Rachel. -You have to talk to her.
不行，经过那晚的事之后 感觉真的太奇怪了
I can't. Not after the other night. It's too weird.
别告诉她我在这里
Don't tell her I'm here.
别吃那个
Don't eat that!
-嘿 -嘿，瑞秋
-Hey! -Hey,Rachel.
乔伊在吗？
Is Joey here?
-我没有看到他，你呢？ -没有
-I don't see him. You? -No.
或许他我在糖碗里 乔伊？没有
Maybe he's in the sugar bowl. Joey? Nope.
至少 你们能逗彼此笑
Well,at least you make each other laugh.
-怎么了？ -我一直没见过他，自从他说…
-What's up? -I haven't seen him since he said..
他怎么…你们知道的…
how he,you know..
我不知道 我想他在避我
I don't know,I think he's avoiding me.
为什么地板上会有贝果？
Why is that bagel on the floor?
-我们在玩游戏？ -钱德没穿衣服吗？
-We were playing a game. -Was Chandler naked?
像是在玩 套圈圈游戏吗？
Sort of like a ring-toss kind of situation?
-没错 -什么？不
-Sure! -What? No! No!
好吧，听着，如果你们看到乔伊 能不能告诉他…
All right,listen. If you see Joey,will you just tell him that..?
告诉他我很想他
Tell him I miss him.
-好吧，你听到了吗？ -是啊，裸体贝果游戏？
-Okay. Did you hear that? -Yeah. That naked bagel game?
我不知道 那个洞真的很小
Dude,I don't know. That's a pretty small hole.
-你得跟她谈一谈 -我没办法
-You've gotta talk to her. -I can't.
你们不知道 被拒绝的感觉有多难受
You guys don't know what it's like to get shot down.
我不知道那种感觉？
I don't know what that's like?
我在25岁前一直以为 “我爱你”的反应是“喔，天啊”
Until I was 25,I thought the response to "I love you" was "Oh,crap."
我没有被拒绝过？
No rejection?
我在减肥营时被拒绝过
I got shot down at fat camp.
天啊，饥饿的孩子们 真的很残忍
Boy,kids are mean when they're hungry.
我该怎么办？
So,what do I do?
她是瑞秋 你永远都不要跟她说话吗？
It's Rachel. You're gonna never talk to her again?
那很奇怪，也很可怕 但至少你得试试看
It's weird and it's awkward,but you gotta at least try.
好吧
Yeah,okay.
我忘了这个曾套在你的…
I forgot this was on your..
我们没有玩它
We didn't play it!
本集播出：茶叶算命法
The.One.With.The.Tea.Leaves
主演：珍妮佛安妮斯顿
主演：寇妮考克斯
主演：丽莎库卓
主演：麦特勒布兰
主演：马修派瑞
主演：大卫修蒙
（中央公园 咖啡馆）
我会看你们的茶叶 帮你们算命
I'll look at your tea leaves and tell your fortune.
-你会茶叶算命法？ -我这么做有好几年
-You read tea leaves? -I've done it for years.
后来我放弃 因为我算得太准了
I actually stopped because I was so accurate.
生命的乐趣 之一…
And one of the great joys of life..
就是 不可预测性
is its wondrous unpredictability,you know?
还有 茶叶会让我拉肚子
And also,tea tends to give me the trots.
-我好了，帮我算吧 -好的
-Okay. I'm done. Read mine. -Okay.
我看到一个梯子
I see a ladder.
它的意思不是升职 就是暴力死亡
Which can mean either a promotion or a violent death.
我是主厨 我不可能被升职
I'm the head chef. I can't get promoted.
下一个是谁？
Who's next?
我好了，帮我算
I'm done. Do mine.
好吧
Okay.
好吧，我看到一个圈圈
Oh! Okay,I see a circle.
那表示 你怀了孩子
Which can either mean you're having a baby..
或你会做出科学发现
or you'll make a scientific discovery!
我一直都待在实验室里
Well,I have been spending a lot of time in the lab.
-你的茶叶又告诉你什么呢？菲比 -好吧
-What does yours say,Pheebs? -All right.
哇，耶
Wow! Yay!
我会认识一个男人 而且很快
Oh,I'm gonna meet a guy! And really soon!
他会是我的梦中情人
He's gonna be the man of my dreams.
或许他不是 我昨晚梦到的那个男人
Probably not the guy I had a dream about last night.
有人看到我的衬衫吗？
Has anyone seen my shirt?
它是前开式的衬衫 淡鲑鱼色
It's a button-down,like a faded salmon color?
你是说你的粉红色衬衫吗？
You mean your pink shirt?
淡鲑鱼色？
Faded salmon color?
不，我没有看到你的粉红色衬衫
No,I haven't seen your pink shirt.
我一定把它丢在蒙娜家了 我就知道
I must have left it at Mona's. I knew it!
我想你可以到安泰勒的专卖店（著名休闲服装连锁店）再买一件
I'm sure you can get another one at Ann Taylor's.
它是我最喜欢的衬衫 我爱它
That's my favorite shirt. I love it.
请蒙娜把它还给你
Ask Mona to give it back.
我不知道，或许吧
I don't know. I could.
我们不算是 好聚好散
We didn't really end things on good terms.
我想去她家 就得忘了她告诉我的一件事…
If I went,I'd be ignoring the one thing she asked me to do..
她要我去跳楼自杀
jump up my own ass and die.
等一下
Oh,wait a second,you guys?
我走到哪里 都会看到那个男人
I've been seeing that guy everywhere I go.
我们搭同一班公车 去同一家书局
We take the same bus,go to the same bookstore.
或许他就是我的真命天子
Maybe he's the tea guy.
你们看到了吗？
Did you see that?
他真的在看你 而且他很帅
He totally checked you out! And he is so cute!
我的茶叶出现乡巴佬的图案 那是什么意思？
Mine is a picture of the Village People. What does that mean?
嗨
Hi.
嘿
Hey.
-嗨 -嗨
-Hi. -Hi.
茶叶让菲比拉肚子
Tea gives Phoebe the trots!
我以为 乔伊跟我可以不尴尬…
I thought Joey and l would be okay..
但我们不知道该怎么相处
but we don't know how to be together.
还有 我一直都想这么说
By the way,I've been meaning to say this.
如果你们知道这件事 我真的很希望你们提醒我一下
If you guys knew about this,a heads-up would have been nice.
只要给点提示就够了
Just a little,you know.
“乔伊爱你 做好准备”
"Joey loves you. Be prepared."
-抱歉 -下次别再犯了
-Sorry. -Well,for next time.
-那真的很难，但情况会有改善的 -你怎么知道？
-It's tough,but things will improve. -How do you know?
如果情况恶化…
What if it gets worse and worse..
但我们无法共处一室呢？
to the point where we can't be in the same room?
我不善于给好建议
I'm not great at the advice.
要我讽刺你一下吗？
Can I interest you in a sarcastic comment?
要起司吗？
Some cheese?
亲爱的，为什么布鲁斯史普林斯汀的CD 会放在凯特史帝文斯的盒子里？
Honey,why is the Bruce Springsteen CD in the Cat Stevens case?
如果我找不到正确的盒子 我会随手拿一个盒子来装
If I can't find the right case,I use the nearest one.
-凯特史帝文斯的CD在哪里？ -詹姆士泰勒的盒子里
-Where is the Cat Stevens CD? -The James Taylor case.
-那张CD在哪里？ -我帮你节省一些时间
-Where is that CD? -I'll save you time.
那200张CD 没有一张放在正确的盒子里
Two hundred CDs,not one of them in the right case.
好吧，不需要慌张 大家深呼吸
Okay. No need to panic. Deep breaths,everyone.
我们只需要把CD 放在正确的盒子里
We'll just have to put the CDs in their right cases.
那么做的话 应该能将CD排好
If we do that,we should come up with some kind of order.
比如按照字母排列或音乐流派
Y’know alphabetically or by genre?
我们得谈一谈这件事
We have to talk this through.
天啊，你们真的有问题 我为你们感到难过
Oh,my God,you have such problems! I feel so terrible for you!
好吧，对不起
All right. Okay,I'm sorry.
你们两个 满脑子都是这件令人不舒服的事
You're both focusing on this uncomfortable thing.
改变一下话题
Change the subject.
让他谈别的事
Get him talking about something else.
对，那挺有道理的
Yeah,that makes sense.
或许你在工作上有问题 需要他的建议…
Maybe you need his advice on a work problem..
-我可以那么做 -很好
-I could do that. -Good.
《迈阿密风云》（80年代的警察故事肥皂剧）的原声带？ 真的吗？
The Miami Vice soundtrack? Really?
那是唱片行的赠品
They were just giving those away at the store.
我得拿钱去换
In exchange for money.
嘿
Hey.
我真的不知道该跟你说什么
I really don't know what to tell you.
或许乔伊可以帮你 解决工作上的大问题
Maybe Joey could help you out with your big work problem.
-什么？ -对，乔伊，她…
-What? -Yeah,Joey,she's..
瑞秋工作上有个大问题 那真的很伤脑筋
Rachel's got this big work problem. It is a head-scratcher.
你知道吗？我们想赶上晚餐预约 就得马上出发
Know what? If we're gonna make dinner,we're gonna have to leave.
对，乔伊 或许你可以帮她
Yeah,Joey,maybe you could help her out.
-好吧 -你知道吗？
-Okay. -Oh,and you know what?
你帮忙 解决这个问题时…
While you're helping solve this problem..
或许你想手边找些事来说 我是不小心想到的…
you might want to do something with your hands. Like,off the top of my head..
譬如说将CD 放到正确的盒子里
maybe put the CDs in their right cases.
来吧
Here we go.
你工作上出了大问题？
So you have a big work problem?
对，那是…
Yeah. It's,uh..
Yeah,it's,uh..
真的没什么
You know,it's nothing.
好吧
Okay.
我想我该走了
So I think I'm gonna take off.
不，乔伊，等一下，我有问题 它真的很严重，是…
No,wait,Joey,it is. It's something. It's..
是我的老板
It's my boss.
-是吗？ -对，跟…
-Yeah? -Yeah. And,uh..
跟我的宝宝
And my baby.
是吗？
Yeah?
我老板想买我的宝宝
My boss wants to buy my baby.
什么？我的天啊
What? Oh,my God!
我知道，我跟你说过了 这真的是个大问题
I know,I told you,it's a really big problem!
-他要买你的宝宝？ -你能相信吗？
-He wants to buy your baby? -Can you believe that?
-那太疯狂了 -我就是那么跟他说的
-That's crazy. -That's what I told him!
-怎么会发生这种事？ -我会告诉你
-How did this even happen? -Well,I'll tell you.
我老板跟他太太 他们不孕，所以…
See,my boss and his wife,they can't have children,so..
在圣诞派对上 我们碰到了面…
And then when we were at the Christmas party..
他喝醉了跟我说 “瑞秋，我要买下你的宝宝”
he got drunk and said to me,"Rachel,I want to buy your baby."
你说你老板跟宝宝 有问题的时候…
When you said it was a problem about your boss and the baby..
我以为 你是指请产假的问题
I figured it was about maternity leave.
对
Oh. Yeah.
对，那样子 问题简单多了
Yeah,that would have been a much simpler problem.
-你好 -是你，我走到哪里都会碰到你
-Oh,hello. -Oh,it's you. I see you everywhere.
我是吉米，吉米尼尔森
I'm Jim. Jim Nelson.
嗨，吉米吉米尼尔森 我是菲比菲比布非
Hi,Jim-Jim Nelson. I'm Phoebe-Phoebe Buffay.
-我们最近常见面 -对
-We've seen each other a lot lately. -Yes.
或许明天晚餐时我们也能碰面 八点可以吗？
Maybe we'll see each other at dinner tomorrow. Around 8:00?
或许会吧
Well,maybe we will.
蒙娜
Mona?
如果我是鲑鱼色衬衫 我会在哪里？
Okay,if I were a salmon shirt,where would I be?
上游
Upstream.
该死 没有人听到我的好笑话
Damn,nobody's here for my good ones.
抱歉我把酒 洒到你的衬衫上
I am so sorry I spilled wine all over your shirt.
-没关系 -不，它还是湿的
-It's okay. -No,it's still wet.
我得把它拿去洗干净免得留下印子 我去找件衣服借你
Let me get it out before it sets. I have something you could wear.
拿去吧
Here.
我真的不想 穿女人的衬衫
I don't know if I want to wear a woman's shirt.
-那是男人的衬衫 -可怕的粉红色
-That's a man's shirt. -Awfully pink.
那不是粉红色
It's not pink!
亲爱的 我们注定要在一起
Honey,we are so meant to be together.
-我们都有安妮的原声带 -亲爱的，那都是你买的
-We both have the Annie soundtrack. -Honey,both yours.
谢谢你给我关于乔伊的建议
Hey,great advice on that Joey thing.
-你说工作的问题了吗？ -真的是太棒了
-The work problem? -lt was perfect.
我觉得他是我的朋友
It felt like he was my friend.
-你说你有什么问题？ -那不重要
-What problem did you say you have? -Oh,that's not important.
重点是 我想一切都会没事
The point is,I think everything's gonna be okay.
需要我效劳吗？
May I help you?
你觉得你可以买走 我朋友的宝宝？
You think you can just buy my friend's baby?
我们一直巧遇真的很有趣吧？ 那就像是有人要我们在一起
Isn't it funny how we kept meeting? It's as if someone wants us together.
没错，那就是我
Someone does. Me.
聪明的家伙，做的好
Witty banter. Well done. Good.
-跟我谈谈你自己 -好吧，我是按摩师
-Tell me a little bit about yourself. -Okay. I'm a masseuse.
-我以前在这个地方工作… -你喜欢参加派对吗？
-And I used to work at this place.. -Do you like to party?
我喜欢派对
I like parties.
你很狂野，对吧？
You're wild,aren't you?
-对，我猜是有一点 -那没有什么，我也很狂野
-Yeah,I guess. A little. -Ain't no thing. I'm wild too.
总之…
So anyway..
我住在纽约 我猜那有点狂野…
I've lived in New York,somewhat wildly,I guess..
我从14岁就住在这里
for,well,since I was 14.
抱歉我盯着你不放
I'm sorry. I'm staring.
因为你有双最漂亮的眼睛
It's just that you have the most beautiful eyes.
-别说了 -还有你的胸部
-Oh,stop it. -And your breasts!
好吧
Okay.
听着，你有点太快了
Look,you're coming on a little strong.
我会解开你的疑虑
I'll give you the benefit of the doubt.
宇宙要我们在一起
The universe wants us to be together.
我们为什么不开始呢？ 你可以跟我谈谈你自己
Why don't we start over? You can tell me about yourself.
-好吧 -好吧
-All right. -Okay.
我写给小孩子看的…
I write erotic novels..
色情小说
for children.
-什么？ -它们非常不受欢迎
-What? -They're wildly unpopular.
我的天啊
Oh,my God!
或许你会想知道 我是个博士
Also,you might like to know I have a Ph.D.
-真的吗？ -对，它真的很大…
-Wow! You do? -Yep. A pretty huge..
够了
All right.
-嘿 -乔伊，听我说
-Hey. -Joey,honey,listen.
谢谢你昨天跟我谈 那对我来说意义重大
Thanks for talking to me yesterday. It meant a lot.
别客气 我得告诉你…
Not a problem. Just so you know..
那家伙不会再为了宝宝的事 来烦你了
that guy won't be bothering you about that baby thing anymore.
-什么？ -我已经解决了问题
-What? -Let's just say I took care of it.
我们得谈一谈
Let's say more.
别担心，我好好地跟他谈过
Don't worry. I told him,very nicely:
“你不能买别人的宝宝 别闹了”
"You don't go buying people's babies! So back off!"
-什么？ -什么？
-What? -What?
不
No,no,no!
他不想买我的宝宝 那是我编出来的
He doesn't want to buy my baby! I made that up!
什么？为什么？
What? Why?
这样我们才有话题聊
So we would have something to talk about!
你想不出来 别的借口吗？
And you couldn't think of anything else?
你说你老板 要买你的宝宝？
You said your boss wants to buy your baby?
你对我老板大叫 我会被开除，我该怎么办？
You yelled at my boss! I'll lose my job! What am I gonna do?
你可以卖掉你的宝宝
You could always sell your baby.
我不敢相信你会去找我老板 我会被开除
I can't believe you brought my boss into it! I'll be fired!
-你骗我 -是她要我那么做的
-You lied to me! -Well,she told me to!
钱德有两张安妮的原声带
Chandler has two copies of Annie!
我的天啊
Oh,my God!
-罗斯 -嗨
-Ross! -Hello!
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
希望你们听了能够有点安慰 我没有自摸
Not touching myself,if that makes anyone less uncomfortable.
好吧，我会打电话给你
Okay,then. I'll call you.
早安，你找我？
Morning. You wanted to see me?
请进，坐下
Please,come in. Have a seat.
-听着，则纳先生… -让我先说吧
-Look,Mr. Zelner.. -It's best I speak first.
好吧
Yeah.
人事部的李 将是我们谈话的见证人
Lee from Human Resources is here as a witness to our conversation.
天啊
Oh,God.
如果我有暗示过你 我想买你的宝宝…
If I in any way implied that I wanted to buy your baby..
我很抱歉，好吗？
I am sorry. Okay?
上星期我问你 你的“预”产期是什么时候…
Last week,when I asked you when your due date was..
我并没有那个意思 要告诉你我想“预谋”你的宝宝
I certainly did not mean that I felt that I was "due" your baby.
我希望清楚地告诉你…
I want to be very clear..
我了解 她是你的宝宝…
that I understand that it's your baby..
我不能买下她
and it is not mine to purchase.
只要把话说清楚就好了
Well,as long as we are clear about that.
到了
There it is.
-这不是你常去的洗衣店 -我知道
-Not your regular cleaners. -I know.
那个怪胎会去那里 我得找新的洗衣店
That creep goes there. I had to find a new one.
我还得找新的银行 成人书店，杂货店…
I have to find a new bank,adult bookstore,grocery store..
-什么？ -新的杂货店
-What? -A new grocery store.
宇宙说我会认识一个好男人 那是真的吗？
The universe said I'd meet a nice guy. I got that?
我上天堂后 一定会痛扁它
When I get up there,I'm gonna kick some ass.
你会认识某人的 如果我能找到好男人，你也可以
You'll meet someone. If I can meet a great guy,so can you.
对，我们都可以，也都会做到
Yeah,we both can. And we both will.
-你不必进来 -你在开玩笑吗？
-You didn't have to come in. -You kidding?
他们在这里把衣服洗干净 对我来说这里就像是迪士尼乐园
This is where they get out stains. This is like Disneyland for me.
我要到这里 看干净衬衫跳舞
I'm gonna be over here watching the dance of the clean shirts.
对不起 我想你掉了…
Excuse me. I think you dropped..
-哇 -什么？
-Wow! -What?
抱歉 你真的是美得不可思议
Sorry. You're just so incredibly beautiful.
我也这么觉得 但又能怎么办呢？
Well,I'm sorry about that too. But what are you gonna do?
别觉得我疯了 我本来是要帮你捡这个
Don't think I'm crazy,but I was meant to pick this up.
-你相信那种事吗？ -有一点
-Do you believe in that kind of thing? -A little.
你说的对
Now you're talking.
-你要去喝咖啡吗？ -我很乐意，我去跟我朋友说一声
-Want to go for coffee? -I'd love to. Let me tell my friend.
是墨水印子 我能看着你把它洗干净吗？
An ink stain! Can I watch how you get this out?
她一定是离开了
She must have left.
-所以呢？发生了什么事？ -没事了
-So? What happened? -It's all gonna be okay.
他们很高兴我不告他们 我还能多放一个月领薪产假
They're so happy I'm not suing,I got an extra month paid maternity leave.
只要我知道 那些钱绝不是…
So long as I understand the money should not be construed..
这个宝宝 或其他宝宝的订金
as a down payment on this or any other child.
罗夫罗兰 真的想尽办法…
Ralph Lauren is going out of their way..
要证明 他们不是贩婴集团
to show they're not in the baby-buying business.
-能让我们独处一下吗？ -你要把我踢出我家的客厅？
-Give us a minute? -Kicking me out of my living room?
对
Yeah.
我会在那里
I'll be in there.
抱歉我骗了你 我只是希望事情…
I'm sorry I lied to you. I was just trying to make things..
我知道
I know. I know.
你的方法的确有效
It kind of worked.
我不知道你是怎么想的 但我一直没想到我们的事
I don't know about you,but I haven't thought about our thing.
对，你说的对
Yeah,you're right.
对，我们又恢复了 “朋友”的样子
Yeah. It's kind of been like "us" again,a little bit.
-我喜欢，我很想念那段时光 -我也是
-Yeah,I know. I've missed that. -Me too.
我没有想到 自己怎么会…
I haven't thought about how I put myself out there..
跟你说那些话 你跟我的感觉不同…
and said that stuff. How you didn't feel the same..
那真的很可怕
and how it was really awkward.
我的妇产科医生想杀我
My gynecologist tried to kill me.
编号是J437-A
Item J437-A.
颜色，冬莓色
Color: winterberry.
听着 过来，来吧…
Hi,listen. Come here. Come..
关于昨天的事我很抱歉
I'm so,so sorry about yesterday.
但我不是跟你说过 不要在门外留备份钥匙吗？
But what did I tell you about leaving your key outside the door like that?
还好那是我 不是别人
I mean,you're lucky it was me and not someone else.
我想那么说太重了一点
I guess lucky is too strong a word.
总之蒙娜，我真的很抱歉 那只是…
Anyway,Mona,I'm really,really sorry. It's just..
听着，你不必道歉 我了解你为什么会去那里
Listen,you don't have to apologize. I understand why you were there.
-真的吗？ -对，你还对我有感觉
-You do? -Yeah. You still have feelings for me.
老实说 我也对你还有感觉
To be honest,I still have feelings for you.
我希望我们能复合 那是不可能的
I wish we could work it out,but we can't.
你跟瑞秋还有宝宝的事 太复杂了，我只是…
It's too complicated with you and Rachel and the baby. I just..
对我来说没法忍受
It just wasn't meant to be.
天啊，你说的对
Oh,God. You're right.
罗斯，我们得坚强
Ross,we have to be strong.
好吧，我得走了
Okay,I'm gonna go.
我能留下它来怀念你吗？
Can I? To remember you?
不行
No.